To pray, to plead, is to open your face to peace, to rest, to fight, and to fight, to
To find the resources, to clean the life of the human systems in the direction of the human life.
To pray is the deep and human system, to be safe to disappear, to speak to the human beings.
To speak is the reason.
To speak is the community of God who is a person to see and to be safe to disappear.
To speak is the community of God who is a person to see.
Hello, are you folks?
If you want to join in your Bibles, I'll be writing chapter 6 this morning.
Hey, we read from the King James Version and we're sitting here this morning.
Okay.
So, I need at least a week of no irreverent millennial pastor jokes, okay?
Is that fair?
Awesome.
I'm so excited for you to join us.
If you missed last week, we are starting a brand new series.
This is week 2 of a brand new series that will run on and off for about 3 years if the Lord will.
The goal is that we intentionally focus on what we're calling a practice-based discipleship.
The discipleship to Jesus is not just about believing in him, but following him.
This is the invitation that he gave us.
And he would come after me, go on himself, take up his cross, and follow me.
Aim spiritual formation to spending time with Jesus so that we might become like him and do what he did.
If you missed last week's message, it's going to be foundational for the whole series.
So, I'd love for you to go back and check that out all the way.
I believe this is a radical invitation that flies in the face of consumer personality and intellectual-based discipleship.
And it is best experience in community, in small groups.
The small group curriculum that goes along with this actually has a lot of extra content and helpful things.
So, you'll get the most out of it if you do it with a small group.
And if none of those small groups fit your schedule and you still want the time to reach out to me,
I've already given somebody else access for that if it makes any of the groups.
I want you to have this.
I want you to do it with other believers or people who are spiritually seeking Jesus.
The first practice that we're going to cover is prayer.
We're going to do four weeks on prayer.
Those four weeks are titled,
Pray to God.
Pray to us talking with God.
Pray to us listening to God.
And pray to us being with God.
So, that's the roadmap for the next four weeks.
Excited about that.
Let me pray, and then we'll get started.
Father in heaven,
we are so grateful that we have access to your presence.
That we have access to your Holy Spirit,
because of the victory that Jesus won in the cross,
and through his empty sin,
we are designing a closer relationship with you.
We are designing your image to be formed in us,
so that we might see and participate with what you're doing all around us.
This morning, God, as we talk about prayer,
as we think about prayer,
I know we all come to this topic with different thoughts and ideas
and how many of you today,
by your Holy Spirit,
speak to each individual in this room
exactly what you need comes to hear,
to invite them into a deep and delightful prayer life.
God, may we become a people who delight in prayer.
God, may we become a people who speak to each other.
God, may we speak to each other.
A little over a year ago,
a young man by the name of DeMar Hamlin,
some of you may remember this,
until I picked up on the screen,
died on an infield football field
in some of 70,000 in-person families
and close to 20 million people watching online.
And the most, many of you probably remember watching this live,
that left an entire nation feeling depressed, confused,
and that they lost four words.
And the moments following,
it felt like all anyone knew how to do was pray.
Prays were listed up by journalists on live television.
Prays were listed up in circles of NFL players all around the field.
Social media were filled with invitations to stop what you are doing and pray.
This was interesting for me as a spiritual leader,
to watch an entire nation filled with atheists, agnostics,
and nominal cultural Christians all unite in desperation on one common thing.
Prays.
He's a miraculous child of God,
the swift, skilled work of the on-field medical staff.
DeMar was revitalized, taken to a hospital where he was in critical condition for many days.
The expenses made a full recovery,
and he's back in the NFL this year.
This story makes me ponder an important spiritual question:
Why does it seem like it takes moments of desperation to get us to pray?
I think most of us, Christian or not,
whether you're just a spiritual seeker or somebody drugged you or lost him,
we would say that if there is a loving Christian,
we would all love to have a regular, deep, vibrant connection with him in prayer.
Yet, if we're honest,
for most of us, prayer can often feel like a duty more than a delight.
Your pastor's the only one of the ladies morning.
prayer can often feel like a duty more than a delight.
And it comes a lot more natural when we're aware of how desperate we are
than in our regular, busy, everyday lives.
The good news is that it spreads a challenge for you.
If it comes easier when you're desperate and not so easy on a day-to-day basis,
if it feels more like a duty than a delight,
you're all right.
St. Theresa, that one who literally was a monastic nun, like she prayed for a living, says this:
"When it comes to prayer, we're all beginners."
The disciples who had the opportunity to follow God in the flesh around,
one of the main questions we have recorded in Scripture that they specifically asked Jesus was this:
"Teach us to pray."
This is a challenge for many spiritual people, many people who follow Jesus,
clarifying the challenge and the difficulty itself.
With the rest of our time this morning, I want to take Jesus' answer to the disciples' question:
"Teach us to pray."
What information did he give when following that question that might help us turn our prayer life from deity to delight?
What does Jesus want us to know about how to pray?
So, this prayer is recorded twice in the New Testament, once in Luke,
as a direct response to the disciples' question, teach us to pray.
And it's also found here in Matthew, chapter 6.
If you know it and want to say it all with me, I invite you to do so.
So, as you can tell, many of us in the spring are familiar with the words of this prayer.
Jesus Christ, our Father, our Father in heaven,
hallowed be your name,
your kingdom to,
your will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us to save our daily bread,
and so give us our debt,
as we also have forgiven our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from the evil.
So, as you can tell,
in the spring are familiar with the words of this prayer.
Our Protestant culture calls it the Lord's Prayer.
Our Catholic brothers and sisters call it the Our Father.
Like I said, it occurs twice in the New Testament.
In Luke, it is a direct response to the disciples' question,
teach us to pray.
In Matthew, it is at the center of the Sermon on the Mount,
which most scholars and theologians would agree,
the Sermon on the Mount is Christ's central teaching
means of the kingdom of heaven.
So, at the center of Christ's central message on his kingdom
is an example to his disciples of how kingdom people who pray.
Dr. Timothy says this about the Lord's Prayer.
He says, "There is no better summary of the movement or mission of God
.
And yet, for most of us, we've lost the value of these words in our culture
because they've been misused or misappropriated
and these kind of let it drift out of our spiritual lives.
But at the center of Christ's teaching on the kingdom is a prayer.
Teaching us how to pray.
And this makes a lot of sense to me the more that I think about it
that all righteous living and faithfulness to spiritual practices
apart from prayer is dead religion.
All righteous living, all spiritual practices,
it's done apart from communication with,
communion with the Father.
It's dead religion.
A couple of examples.
If you participate in Sabbath on a weekly basis,
but that Sabbath doesn't lead you to communion with God in prayer,
you're just relaxing.
You're not resting in the Lord.
Fasting, apart from prayer, is just starvation.
It's not spiritual.
And on and on we could go.
Prayer is the spiritual practice that all other spiritual practices follow through.
Mark Homer argues that prayer is actually an umbrella term for all a spiritual life with God.
It's the spiritual practice that all other spiritual practices are focused through.
It's the reason why we're starting with it in our series.
That if everything that we do doesn't lead us into the presence of the Father,
in communication with the Father, then we're missing it.
But, if prayer is supposed to be at the center of our spiritual lives,
why does it often feel much more like a deity than a delight?
Many of us in here would much rather go to a Bible study than a prayer to me.
Okay.
If I had to take my best pastoral guess at the biggest obstacle to a healthy and vibrant prayer life
rooted in delight, I would say that it's either because we have a misunderstanding of who God is to us,
or, and or, if you're in my spot, and you're in the real bad spot,
you have a misunderstanding of who God is to you, and you have a misunderstanding of who you are to God.
I mean, the incredible thing about that is that this prayer that Jesus gives us
is full of three truths that he wants us to daily remind ourselves about who God is to us,
and three truths that he wants us to daily remind ourselves about who we are to God.
He says, "You want to have a delightful prayer that you have to regularly, daily,
multiple times a day to remind yourself of who God is to you, and who you are to God."
We've got a beautiful hey statement in the middle that connects those two, and we're just going to,
that's going to be the flow of our message for the rest of the day, right?
Three things Jesus wants us to remind ourselves about who God is to us,
his statement about the distance between who we are to God, who God is to us,
and then three things about who we are to God, okay?
Well, hopefully that makes sense right again. Let's see how we go.
Number one, the first thing that Jesus wants you to daily remind yourself about who God is to you is that God is our Father.
Our Father in heaven, hallowed be you.
So, the disciples ask Jesus, teach us to pray, and although this is really a beautiful,
powerful, fun way on prayer, the disciples might have been a little bit disappointed
because the words that Jesus gives them aren't really new to them.
Many Bible scholars would say that it's actually, the words in the Lord's Prayer
are actually very familiar to many other prayers that they would pray in the temple regularly.
The disciples ask Jesus how to pray.
Jesus, God in the flesh, the Messiah, he's here, teach us how to pray.
Give us some new, exciting way to pray.
He's like, "Read them in praise that they already know."
But essentially, you've got Christ, you know how to pray, you already know how to pray,
but there is one massive twist on Christ's prayer versus the other prayers that they would read in the temple,
and that is how Jesus addresses God.
See, the word for Father in the original text is actually one of the few Aramaic words in the Scriptures.
He's written in Greek.
There's a few Aramaic terms that slip in.
The Aramaic would have been kind of the blue-collar daily language of Jesus.
And this term, Abba, literally is the most enduring and reverent term that a son could have to a father.
God chose not to translate it into Greek because there wasn't a good enough Greek equivalent of this intimate, endearing,
resident, childlike term for the father.
In America today, a lot of good-willed Bible teachers will make the equivalent to daddy.
I think it's helpful.
The only problem is that we stop calling our dad's daddy at a certain age, right?
This guy's family maybe 12, 13, you know, whatever, we're on a spectrum here.
In Aramaic, they wouldn't stop calling their dad Adam.
There was the term that they called him as a child, as an adolescent, and then as an adult.
It was reverent.
It was respectful, but it was also intimate and close.
See, the Jewish cults have had so much fear and reverence for Yahweh
that they refused to even utter his name out loud.
By the time the Second Temple turned around, the time of Zeus and the disciples,
they wouldn't even use God's name that he gave them to use.
Instead, they started using stale titles like Adonai,
who's one of them, like, doctor or spiritual service type,
give us this day or day or day, right?
There's this, like, disconnect relationally.
And Jesus comes in to the disciples and he says,
"When you come to God, when you come to Yahweh, Creator of all,
saying you, you are invited to come into his presence as your follower."
So, God, who loves you deeply and wants a relationship with you,
this is a new idea that he's introducing.
He wants his disciples to daily remind themselves
that who God is to them is that he is a loving father
who is inviting his children into their presence.
Scholar J.J., Scholar J.J. says,
There is not a single example of the use of Adonai as an address to God in the whole of Jewish poetry.
Jesus is introducing a new idea to his disciples.
You don't come to the Father as doctor or service or reverend.
And no matter what your earthly relationship with your father is like,
my sense is that we all have this work view somewhere down the line of what a father is and what a father isn't.
And we place false images about God based on our experiences with our earthly fathers.
No matter how great of a relationship you have with your father, he's not as good as God is.
And so, Jesus wants you to daily strip yourself of whatever warped of meaning you might have about how God thinks of you.
And he wants to really invite you to engage with this idea that God loves you unconditionally as you are.
Last week I asked you guys throughout the week to consider reading through the prodigal son passage in Luke chapter 15.
This is such a beautiful imagery of what Jesus says is true about the father.
That no matter how much you rebel, no matter how much you sin against the father, the father's desire is for you to be with you.
The younger son runs away and lives a rebellious life.
The older son stays close and lives a religious life.
Neither of them desire to be with the father.
And yet, all throughout the story, the father is desperately inviting his children to be with them.
This is true of your heavenly father.
He wants you to be in his presence.
No matter what you've done.
No matter what you're currently doing.
No matter what you're going to do tomorrow.
The father loves you.
And Jesus wants you to daily remind yourself of that perfect love.
When you think about what God says about himself.
In Exodus, Moses asks to see the glory of the Lord.
And there's this whole story where you can't see him face to face.
God shows up and the one thing that he wants to know, Moses, is true about him.
He says this, "The Lord, the Lord's passionate and grace is slow to anger and abounding in love."
This is the character of our heavenly heart.
Is this how we approach God in prayer?
Do you truly view him as a perfect loving father who invites us into his presence no matter what we've done?
I love what Bethany Youngman says.
He says that one of the reasons prayer can be so difficult is because we're not being honest about how we see God and how we believe God is God.
We often hold a false narrative about God and how he truly feels about us.
If we feel like we have to perform for God, I don't think we will ever seemingly enter into prayer in the intimate way that God desires for us.
He says we need a fresh revelation for how much God loves us.
And that's what Jesus is giving his disciples in this prayer, a daily fresh reminder, a fresh revelation of how much God loves them.
Jesus wants you and I to have a daily fresh revelation when we enter into the presence of God.
He wants us to remind ourselves of God's unconditional, compassionate, flow to anger, patient love.
Imagine how this prayer, this type of prayer might help us turn our prayer life and beauty to the light.
So, first of all, Jesus wants us to remind ourselves of that God is Father.
The second is that God is closer than you think.
Our Father in heaven, hallowed be your name.
The Greek words for heaven, the tricky one that sounds like in our language and in our culture,
heaven also means a far away, distant place in the sky where we go when we die.
And all the hell, there is a heavenly realm where God dwells.
We've read about that in Isaiah chapter 6.
God is also what theologians call omnipresent.
Anybody feel like learning a new word today, but the title will never be used.
All right.
God is omnipresent.
He is everywhere at all times.
The word in heaven can just as easily be translated in the air.
All around us.
As close as our next breath.
Holy is your name.
I think another reason we often view prayer as duty rather than delight is because we often view God as distant and far away,
and too busy to help come to focus on our needs and our essence for them.
Anybody get anxiety around making phone calls?
I think it's a millennial thing.
I don't know.
Especially when I'm calling somebody about like a bill or like a customer service thing, right?
And I just like, I get this like, and this dread and this duty of like, my wife has asked me with calling this person.
And if I don't, she's going to ask me about it.
So it's a duty, right?
It's something that I have to do.
I dread it.
And oftentimes I call these customer service lines and what happens?
You're on hold.
And you're getting transferred and nobody actually knows the answer to your question.
It's funny that you actually know how their systems work better than the people that work for them, right?
And I think sometimes if we're on this, this is how we do creative.
Like, we don't think about it this way, but when we come and take the presence of God, it's like we're coming into this place where there's so much going on.
There's so much business.
God's too far away.
He's too distant.
There's too much on his plate.
If he actually cares about what's going on in my life, does this actually do anything for me or for him?
As I was preparing to this sermon, I was working from home on Thursday with the baby.
They were home and came back and I got a notification from the ring that day at home.
And so I just popped into the ring camera and I just said, "Hey, like, what's going on?
How's life?
How did the same go?
You know, like, how's the baby?"
And like, as I was doing that and comparing to the sermon, I was a great example for what prayer is like for the Father of Jesus.
He's always present.
He's always available.
We can just drop in at any moment, any time.
Our Father in heaven is closer than you think.
Jesus wants you to daily remind yourself that God is a Father who is always present, eager, and available for you to communicate with him.
Imagine how tough and interesting you have got.
A nearness to us might help us turn my cares from duty to the light.
The third thing Jesus wants us to remind ourselves of is that God is holy.
All around us, holy is your name.
Holy is your name.
Holy will be your name.
This is a verb that Jesus is asking us to do to make Jesus' name holy.
Holy means holy.
You, set apart, are different than any earthly thing.
God is different.
He is set apart.
He is holy.
He is worthy of your praise and your adoration.
There are an endless number of adjectives that we could use to share about what makes God different from us.
Right?
Like we could just rattle off adjectives that make God different from us.
And we would be here all day, probably tomorrow, the next day, and the day after that.
But there's one adjective that I think is most crucial for our understanding of what makes God set apart from us that helps us in the world.
And that is his perfect and eternal consistency.
That is unchanging.
He is always the same.
You know what you should express when you enter in his presence and prayer.
And how many other of our relationships work like that?
How many other of our relationships work where we go to a person and we know exactly what we're going to get.
No matter how bad of a day they have.
No matter how good of a day they have.
No matter what's going on in their life or in their mind.
We get different, varying reactions.
With God, that is my spirit.
God's name, Yahweh, literally means I am the unchanging one.
The one who always has been and the one who always will be.
God is consistent in his character.
We know what we can expect when we enter this presence.
God is the loving Father who is near to offer.
He is unsanized by our behavior or our circumstances.
And that's totally different than any other relationship we have.
Oftentimes when we read this, I've had people talk to me about this.
I've had people talk to me about this.
And I've had people talk to me about this.
There are 14 words in our Scripture.
Let's read it.
"Your kingdom come.
Your will be done on earth as it is in heaven."
Remember at the beginning we said that the prayer is the central message of the central message
of the gospel, about the kingdom of God.
It's the central message, right?
And just look at the center of the prayer.
These words.
This is a summary of all that God is doing and will do in his creation.
This phrase ultimately acknowledges that there's something that we're experiencing on earth
that isn't as God intended it to be.
There is a disconnect between us and God that wasn't intended to exist.
And God has made a plan and he's performing that plan to restore his will on earth as it is in heaven.
There's a disconnect.
It's true.
It's very.
We are not experiencing what God intended for us to experience.
And prayer is an invitation for us to acknowledge them and reclaim the trees that are spirits,
that spiritually exist now, that will physically exist in the eternal kingdom.
God is restoring and will ultimately restore his will on earth as it is in heaven.
And prayer is an opportunity for us to express our trust in him to execute that plan.
And it's an opportunity for us to partner with him in that plan.
The best way I think illustrated is for those of you that are familiar with the Old Testament,
you know, Israel is in slavery to Egypt.
God delivers them from the slavery to Egypt.
He gave them across the Red Sea.
And then they're wandering.
They wander and they wander and they wander,
daily following the presence of God by a cloud of smoke, by a cloud of smoke, by a cloud of smoke,
by a cloud of smoke, known as in heaven, right?
Awaiting this promise for him, filled with smoke and honey.
And I think what we're doing here when we say that for kingdom come here,
we'll be done in the aces of the earth in heaven.
We're putting ourselves in that place.
Those of us that are followers of Jesus, those of us that would pray to be Christians,
we have been set free from the slavery of death and sin and the grave we have and hope for the future.
But, anybody else feel like your daily life is like wandering in the wilderness?
Right, everyone?
Right?
Like there's two realities at play here.
Jesus has set you free from death and the grave and from slavery to sin.
You can walk in daily freedom, keeping your eyes on the presence of God and your lives
and trusting Him to provide daily manna from heaven.
And you are eagerly anticipating a day where He is going to restore all sins the way He intended them to be.
And in that intermediate field, we're invited to pray part of your kingdom, your way and being on the purpose as it is in heaven.
We're acknowledging before the Heavenly Father that we are experiencing things that are not good.
And we trust Him to restore everything to believe in what He intended it to be.
Does that sound good?
Okay.
So, this new statement here is what Jesus wants us to know is true about us versus what Jesus wants us to know what is true about God.
Again, I'm going to get through this.
That's not enough.
Day these things, please.
All right.
Now, three things that God or Jesus wants us to give you to remind ourselves is true about us.
More.
We need God's provision.
Give us this day our daily bread.
I don't know about you, but I think I often avoid food because I'm distressed and I'm busy.
I'm too overwhelmed by the worries and anxieties of this world.
I'm in a disillusion that if I just work harder or put the right decisions into the right calculation, then everything will work out.
I've been doing that for 12 years now as an adult and it still hasn't worked out.
I've talked to some of you that are older than me and you've told me that it's still not working out for you either.
So, we'll just trust that it's not going to work out.
So, praying for God to provide us with daily bread is a reminder that God is in control and that you and I can not add a single dollar to our bank account or a single second back to our cost by worrying.
It is an acknowledgement of our total reliance on God who is on the altar in heaven, all alone in us.
Later in this chapter, Jesus explains all this teaching and reread it in Matthew 6:25.
He says, "Therefore, I tell you, don't be anxious about your life.
What you will eat or what you will drink, worry about your body, what you will put on.
Is not a life worthy to you and the body more than a clothing?
Look at the birds of the air.
They need to sow nor reap nor gather into the barns.
And yet your heavenly Father receives them.
Are you not more valuable than me?
And which of you, by being anxious, can add a single hour to his life to him?
Why are you anxious about clothing?
Consider the worries of the field and how they grow.
And neither toil nor spin.
Yet I tell you, even Solomon, in all of his glories, my little age, I want to be.
But as God so fills the grass of the field, which today is allowed and tomorrow will be thrown in the oven,
will he not much more clothe you or you as what he said?
Therefore, do not be anxious than what will we eat or what will we drink or what will we wear?
For the Gentiles seek after all these things.
And your heavenly Father knows that you need them.
But seek first God's kingdom and his rights, and all these things will be added to you.
Jesus wants us to daily remind ourselves that God loves us, and he will provide for our needs, and that prayer is a much healthier approach we would.
But daily reminding ourselves that we are in need of God's provision, I think, will help us bring our place and duty to the light.
And will ultimately lead to what Paul calls "peace that passes under Satan."
And then a lot of us, we read that Scripture, and then we get in the spot where we're desperate, where life is like all over the place, not working out the way that we stood.
And we throw up one trail, and we're like, "What's that peace that passes under Satan?"
I need it.
I need some of that peace that passes under Satan.
You guys can do that.
You guys can miraculously work through one trail to provide to you a peace that passes under Satan.
But I think in context, if you look at what Paul's saying though, he's saying that a pattern of daily coming into the Father's presence and claim,
give us this day of daily thanks for life, for our physical needs.
That when you have a habit, a pattern, a practice of doing that on a daily and regular routine,
that when things hit the same, when life goes off the rails, that's when you come back into that place.
You're there every single day, and then when life hits hard, you come back to that place,
and that's where you experience this peace that passes understanding.
If you want peace that passes understanding, daily come into the presence of God and acknowledge your needs for his provision.
Number two, we need provision, and we need to receive and extend his forgiveness.
He says, "Forgive us our debts as we offer to use all debtors."
The earth is broken because you are not broken.
Thank you. I appreciate that.
We rebelled against God and his good plans for our lives, and the first step to true restoration is confessing his sin before the Father,
and receiving his forgiveness, understanding his kindness, so that we can extend that forgiveness to others.
This one statement, "Probably these days are going to tell the same as you look properly."
I know some of you are like, "Oh, this puts an effort to me to cause you to come in.
I'm supposed to just put myself back and see if you want any better."
It's not what I'm saying, "We don't have time to do all the new ones."
So, just trust me to say this, for now.
For now, it will never be the life for you until you learn to completely be honest and vulnerable before you have to respond.
With all of your mercy.
Until you truly understand and receive his forgiveness and unconditional grace for that man.
What's hard for us in prayer is that we would get back to the image of God.
God wants you to be naked and untamed before him.
Not because you're innocent by your own doing, but because the blood of Jesus wants you to come.
Come into the presence of the Father, receiving his forgiveness, confessing honestly.
This is what made David in the Old Testament a man after God's own heart.
You know the Old Testament pretty well, and your opinion is that God will call him David and make him through his own heart?
My only one thing to you.
Yeah, seriously.
He's like, of all of the heroes of the saints, of all of the leaders in the Old Testament, morally, he is so correct.
And yet, God calls him a man after his own heart, and you wrestle with it over and over again.
But you read the Psalms, and what David got better than anything else, he failed in so many things.
But wasn't God right his confession?
He brought his stuff before God, honestly, not hiding it.
He hid it at times, and God called him out on it.
And then he brought it before the man.
His desire was to be naked and understand before the Father.
And that's God's desire in us that we would, I don't know, that we would really confess him in honesty about our mess,
and just trust him to take care of it.
So that we can extend it to others.
Pray with this from the beauty to a delight as we learn to daily confess our mess to God,
to be naked and understand before him, so that we can extend that same grace here to others.
I'm doing everything I'm trying this morning.
Yeah, you see how good it's meant.
Lastly, the last thing that Jesus wants us to do and remind ourselves is true about us before God,
is that we need God's victory.
Lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil.
Some translations say deliver us from the evil world.
Every day, you and I are inundated with distractions and deceptions from the world, the flesh, and the devil.
Our culture is trying to disciple us away from our healthy and vibrant relationship with the Lord.
Our flesh constantly tells us that the things we want are more important than the things that our soul needs.
And we need to daily remind ourselves that these things are seeking to steal, kill, and destroy us from the abundant life that Jesus has to offer us.
We need to daily remind ourselves that there is an abundant life that is better than what our flesh desires.
And we need victory from the Father.
We need him, his power.
The same power that raised Jesus from the dead is present in a variable time.
We need to come and daily ask the Lord to give us that power.
To not be petty with our co-workers.
To not wander on the internet at night where no one's at home.
To not use food or substance or alcohol as a thing that secures us temporarily but not eternally.
Whatever your thing is, you need to daily come into the presence of God and ask him for his power and victory over that thing so that you can walk in the abundant life that he's inviting you into.
The death, resurrection, and gift of the Spirit gives you all the power you need to adjust to deception and live into the truth.
Jesus wants us to daily remind ourselves that we are trying to wander and that there are more specific and endless temptations that we're trying to lead us away from God's word for all of us.
Imagine how prayer might come from a duty to a delight when we daily use prayer to access the power of God to live in victory and obedience.
So, to review the prayer, Jesus wants you and me to daily, regularly remind ourselves of who God is to you and who you are to God.
That he is the Abba.
That he's closer than you think.
That he's completely and utterly unique from all through us.
And that the life that we currently experience is not God's reference.
But that he is a plan for redemption and the confession that he's left today.
We await the day when he will return and establish his kingdom on earth forever.
Until that day comes, we acknowledge our daily need for his provision.
Our daily need for his forgiveness.
And our daily need for his power to overcome some people.
I believe that contained in this short prayer is the roadmap for a life lived in the direction of the kingdom of God on earth as it is in heaven.
Think about it.
Most of the troubles in your life, most of your challenges, most of your difficulties, most of your anxiety, your worry, your pain,
and you either having a misunderstanding about who God is or a misunderstanding about who you are.
Most of our interpersonal conflict is because you feel like people are getting in the way of us getting the idea we get.
Get caught off on the road and you say, dude, where I'm going is more important than where you're going, right?
We get into these interpersonal conflicts because we view people as being in the way of getting the thing that God promises to give us.
And so as we're doing, regularly, coming into the presence of God and acknowledging, I have needs and you have all the provision that I need for the needs that I have.
And I am going to trust you with those needs.
And when people get in my way, I am going to see them not as obstacles, but as image-bearers, as gods who probably had a worse day than I did.
And I am going to extend to them the grace and forgiveness, a very small shadow of the grace and forgiveness that you have extended to me.
Another reason we struggle with daily conflicts and anxiety and worries, we take God's justice into our own sins.
They send against the needs, but I am going to make sure that they give what is coming to them.
Do you consider that you remind yourself of the justice of the Lord?
Do you use extended forgiveness?
Do you use that you might extend forgiveness to all of us?
I believe as we rediscover the beauty of this model for prayer, as we actually took this prayer seriously, we begin to experience the kingdom of God on earth as it is.
And rather, more and more, as we daily walk into these human values and these human principles, as we await the days that Jesus took home and make it all physically visible.
You know, turn my prayer away from beauty to delight.
And I can speak from experience on most people who are called out, pretty much only ever played high school football teams, and in ritualistic, stale environments.
Over the past month, I have incorporated this prayer into my daily rhythms of love, and it has transformed the way that I do.
Not because I've done anything special other than just kiss Jesus out of his way.
But what he said is, this is how I used to cry, I just decided to try it.
Right?
Not an idea.
And not only ritualistic religions in no way, but this is an indication to remind myself to speak out of his commands.
To remind myself that these things that I'm having on earth are not God's ultimate will, so there's a plan to restore that will on earth as it is in heaven.
And then until that day comes, I'm just going to go.
I'm going to survive everything that I'm having.
Mm-hmm.
One final practical thought.
We did the theology.
The practical thought here is that this isn't just a general teaching of theology about how we should pray, but it's actually, again, a novel thought.
That Jesus invites us to pray with him.
Scott McKnight, theologian, New Testament scholar, says that you could translate what Jesus says here.
When you pray, recite this.
See, most of us in American low-church culture like this, this is low-church, we've lost the beauty of literature in the church.
And those of you that come from high church, you might say, yeah, a lot of you that high church has also lost the beauty of literacy in the church.
The small group content of this week is going to be filled with practical advice for how you can reincorporate literacy, which just means two written titles.
Friends that have been written by people before us.
This one in particular is the main one that the sister wrote it.
God himself.
You can start there.
But then from there, there's other crazy Scriptures and those written by brothers and sisters in the Christian faith throughout the last 2,000 years.
So I'd love for you to reincorporate those speaking to your lives.
Again, that's just my group saying that we'd love for you to do this.
But today's message, I encourage you this week to daily incorporate or recite the alphabet using the jumping off points of your daily rhythms.
Let's pray.
Use it as an invitation to remind yourself of who God is to you, who you are to God.
I want to send them to lead us in a song.
I asked them on page and say thank you for being flexible.
Because I think the song is a healthy invitation to remind ourselves of who God is to us and who we are to God.
For those of you that are really out on liturgy, you're not always out on liturgy as you think.
It's a song that's liturgy.
It's just a true written song that you're singing.
St. Augustine said that when you sing, that he who sings place twice.
And so worship is this invitation to pray to God, the lyrics written by the worship leaders that read our songs.
And so we're going to say listen to that in this important verse, let me invite this prayer to our Father, using it as a jumping off point just to pray into the kingdom values of God's love.
Father in heaven.
Father all around us.
The full unique.
The full of Israel.
We acknowledge your presence and your dream today.
It's not just a scale worship for us.
It's not a scale, intellectual, and deserter.
God, you are here.
And you are here because you love us.
And you have an abundant life for us.
But you are inviting us into.
And daily we wander from that invitation and the deserter presence.
And today we just want to remind ourselves that you are a good father.
And you are here.
And you are here because you love us.
And you have an abundant life for us that you are inviting us into.
And daily we wander from that invitation and the blessed presence.
And today we just want to remind ourselves that you are a good father.
Who is present.
And always.
Your kingdom come and you are Lord.
You join in on earth.
And you are here because you love us.
And you have an abundant life for us.
And you are inviting us into.
And daily we wander from that invitation and the blessed presence.
And today we just want to remind ourselves that you are a good father.
Who is present.
And always.
Your kingdom come and you are Lord.
You join in on earth.
As it is in heaven.
Your kingdom come and you are Lord.
You join in on earth.
As it is in heaven.
Your kingdom come and you are Lord.
You join in on earth.
As it is in heaven.
God.
In a rainbow sky.
There are so many different experiences of the broken creation.
What are people going to stick?
Is that in diagnosis?
recently that they once expected.
And there are people who have lost red ones.
And there are people who are in an interpersonal conflict.
That they can't seem to get out of it.
And there are people who have lost red ones.
And there are people who are in an interpersonal conflict.
That they can't seem to get out of it.
And there are people who have lost red ones.
And there are people who are in an interpersonal conflict.